十月革命和俄国内战结束之后
After the October Revolution and the Russian civil war,
被打败的帝国军队和十万难民
the defeated Imperial army, led by General Vrangel,
由弗兰格尔将军率领
together with more than 100,000 refugees,
在南斯拉夫王国安家落户
found a new home in the Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes.
15000名哥萨克人作为独立的军事力量行动
15,000 Cossacks operated as an independent military force.
他们只听命于弗兰格尔将军和亚历山大国王
They answered only to general Vrangel and the king Alexander.
1921年  南斯拉夫王国  海尔采格港-新黑山
1921. The Port of Herceg-Novi Montenegro, Kingdom of SCS
曾经伟大的国家和军队最后残余
The last remnants of a once great nation and a once great army...
俄罗斯多亏了那些为祖国献出生命的人
Russia lives thanks to those who died for her...
才能继续活下去
And continues to live...
感谢那些为祖国捐躯的人们
thanks to those who live for her.
不要绝望，公爵
Do not despair, Duke...
如果情况允许，明年春天我们将再次发动进攻
God willing, we will take the offensive again next spring.
将军，你的希望是徒劳的，我们已经失败了
General, your hope is vain. We have lost.
接受现实吧
Accept it.
是的... 你肯定接受了
Yes... You surely accepted it.
当我们为俄罗斯流血的时候你却在组织舞会,
While we bled for Russia, you've been organizing balls,
喝着香槟，在角落里和女仆做爱
drank champagne, and humped maids in the corners.
是你输了那场战争，不是我！
You lost that war, not me!
这是我的军队，我的！
It's my army. Mine!
人数虽然不多
It may be small in numbers,
但他们都愿意为俄罗斯献出生命！
but all of them will give their lives for Russia!
将军! 东军和库班军已经登陆了
General! The Don Army Corps and the Kuban Corps have set ashore.
士气良好，货物已送达，我们正在等候指令
Morale is good. The cargo is delivered. We're awaiting orders.
帝国保险箱呢？
And what about the imperial safe?
在船长的船舱里，这是钥匙
It's in the captain's cabin. Here's the key.
有两个人日夜看守
Two men are guarding it round-the-clock.
塞尔维亚的兄弟军队
The brotherly Serbian army
将我们的军队安置在他们的营房里
will accommodate our corps in their barracks.
亚历山大国王已经答应
King Alexander has promised
提供所有可能的援助和支持
all possible assistance and support.
先生们，这里现在是我们的家
Gentlemen, this is our home now.
七年后
SEVEN YEARS LATER
-注射吗啡时小心点 -别说了
- Easy with the morphine. - Knock it off.
我已经不是你的丈夫了
I'm not your husband anymore.
上帝不承认离婚，所以你还是我的丈夫
God doesn't recognize divorce. You're still my husband.
也许上帝不承认，但是你现任丈夫…
Perhaps before God, but before your current husband...
如果你不喜欢，我可以不来
If you don't like it, I can stop coming.
你了解我...我只做我不喜欢的事
You know me... I only do what I don't like.
- 下周见? - 走的时候别忘了锁门
- See you next week? - Don't forget to lock the door.
1928年 贝尔格莱德  塞尔维亚
1928. BELGRADE, SERBIA
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS AND SLOVENES
科鲁巴拉? 卡杰马卡兰？
Kolubara? Kajmakcalan?
贝尔格莱德
Belgrade.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第一集
Black Sun
你在干什么? 那是神圣的！
What are you doing? That's sacred!
别碰它！
Don't touch it!
亲爱的上帝... 是你？
Dear Lord... Is that you?
鬼牌在哪儿? 继续吧
Where's the jack? Go on, play.
今晚运气不好，来吧
No luck tonight. Come on, play.
早上好，抱歉打扰你
Good morning. Sorry to interrupt you.
我刚开始赢你就来打断我
You did interrupt just when I started winning.
- 你有什么事? - 抱歉，你说什么？
- What do you want? - I beg your pardon?
抱你妈个头，你有什么事来这么早？
Beg your mum. What brings you here so early?
米利萨夫，接电话！
Milisav, answer the phone!
我来警察局刑侦组报到
I have to report to the Crime Police Department.
抢劫在走廊尽头，谋杀在左边第二扇门
Robberies are down the hall, murders second door to the left.
你不明白... 我是技术警察组派来的
You didn't understand... I was sent by the Technical Police.
米利萨夫，你能接一下电话吗！
Milisav, would you please answer that phone!
他们让我六点钟来这里
They told me to come here at 6 o'clock...
警察局
Police Department.
我来早了一点，我还没…
Anyway, I came a bit earlier, and I haven't...
我还没有自我介绍…
I haven't introduced myself...
什么时候？
When?
技术警察局督察 斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇
Inspector Stanko Pletikosich, Technical Police.
前来报到
Reporting for duty.
就像我常说的，有价值的人都在战争中牺牲了
Like I always say, valuable people got killed in the war.
- 你刚才说技术警察? - 是的，我在洛桑毕业
- Technical police, you said? - Yes, I graduated in Lausanne...
俄罗斯教堂发生一起谋杀案
A murder at the Russian church.
祝你第一个案子好运
Good luck on your first case.
- 走吧，别喝了 - 去找塔纳西耶维奇警官
- C'mon, leave that brandy and move. - Find inspector Tanasiyevich.
塔纳西耶维奇警官? 他的办公室在哪里？
Inspector Tanasiyevich? Where is his office?
- 打烊了 - 早上好
- We're closed. - Good morning.
打烊了，伙计
It's closing time, man. Get out.
我来找塔纳西耶维奇警官
I'm looking for insp. Tanasiyevich.
他不在，我会告诉他的
He's not here. I'll pass your message.
- 走吧! - 等一下..
- Now, get out! - Just a second...
原来是自己人! 抱歉，我只是在保护他
Ah, you're one of us! Sorry, I was just protecting him.
- 外面有很多混蛋找他麻烦 - 没关系
- Lots of jerks out there. - It's alright.
他在那儿，请把他带走吧
There he is, at that table. Get him out of here, please.
但是要小心…
But be careful though...
你是安德拉 · 塔纳西耶维奇吗？
Are you Andra Tanasiyevich?
通常是我在问问题
Usually I'm the one asking questions.
我是斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇，你们的新同事
I'm Stanko Pletikosich, your new colleague.
好吧，请坐，亲爱的同事
Well, have a seat, dear colleague.
喝一杯，我请客
And have a drink. On me.
这钱花得值
Now that's money well spent.
- 你说吧 - 发生了一起谋杀案
- I'm listening. - There's been a murder.
姓名？
Name?
斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇，技术警察
Stanko Pletikosich, Tech. Police.
我问你受害人的姓名
The victim's name, for Christ's sake!
真是奇怪的年代，过去人们在家里杀人
Strange times... People used to kill each other at homes,
或者在黑暗的小巷里用斧头杀人
or in the dark alleys. Properly, with an axe.
现在呢? 竟然在教堂里杀人！难怪国家现在一团糟
And nowadays? At the church! No wonder country is in shit.
我们得罪了上帝，这就是原因
We've sinned against God, that's why.
是上帝先开始的，我们只是在反击
He started first. We just fought back.
不要再亵渎上帝了
Stop blaspheming.
他两次救了你的命
He saved your life twice.
那我还真是谢谢他老人家了
Well that was one hell of a favour.
米利萨夫，准备开车！
Milisav, start the car!
等等，我和你一起去！
Wait, I'm coming with you!
早上好，检察官先生，这是你的日程表
Good morning, Mr. Prosecutor. This is your schedule.
- 部长中午会过来 - 好的
- The minister will be here at noon. - Okay.
久基奇先生，这是法庭的裁决
Mister Djukich, here's the court's decision.
这么快？
Already?
恭喜你，斯托扬，干得漂亮
Congratulations, Stoyan. Great job.
- 我已经尽力了… - 很好，这样…
- I'm doing my best here... - Okay, here's the plan.
久基奇先生， 乔洛维奇上校在等你
Mr. Djukich, Colonel Djolovich is waiting for you.
让他等着! 我等了他们一辈子
Let him! I waited for them my whole life.
在我离开之前，把这个再打印三份
Retype this in three copies, before I leave.
准备好，我们开完会就走
Be ready, we'll leave after the meeting.
- 给你 - 谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
乔洛维奇上校！
Colonel Djolovich!
我醒着呢，只是让眼睛休息一下，说吧…
I'm awake. Just resting my eyes. Speak up...
乔洛维奇，我建议你认真对待这次会议
Djolovich, I advise you to take this meeting very seriously.
我上一次睡觉是在七年前
Last time I slept was seven years ago.
久基奇，IMRO（马其顿内部革命组织）在斯科普里杀害了一名参议员
Djukich, the IMRO killed a senator in Skopje.
你叫我来最好是有很重要的事
I hope you have a good reason for bringing me here.
一位俄罗斯牧师昨晚在他的教堂里被谋杀了
A Russian priest was murdered in his church last night.
真的? 你真以为你知道我不知道的事？
Really? You really think you know something I don't?
我们知道警察根本破不了案
We know the police won't find the killer.
沃兰赫尔的哥萨克人会亲手伸张正义
Vrangel's Cossacks will take justice into their own hands.
我们应该在他们复仇之前把他们遣散
We should demobilize them before they get the revenge.
那不是你的工作
That's not your job.
我的工作是执法！
My job is law enforcement!
哥萨克人已经走了很多年了,
And the Cossacks have been walking around for years,
全副武装，身着制服，警察都无法阻止他们
armed and in uniforms. The police can't even stop them.
和日瓦科维奇将军谈谈，他必须撤销哥萨克人的豁免权
Talk to General Zhivkovich. He has to revoke their immunity.
我在安全部门工作
I work for the Security service.
你是州检察官
You're the state prosecutor.
如果我没记错，你的工作是很明确的:
As far as I remember, your tasks were clearly defined:
马其顿分裂主义者和鸦片
Macedonian separatists and opium.
没有人记得我们在第一次世界大战中的英雄事迹
Nobody mentions our heroism from the Great War,
他们只把我们当成走私贩和鸦片贩子
they see us as smugglers and opium dealers.
当然，因为俄罗斯人和马其顿人在这里卖鸦片
Sure they do, when Russians and Macedonians are selling opium here.
对付这些鸦片贩子，我们去对付俄国人
Deal with them, leave Russians to us.
日瓦科维奇将军正在处理了，不可能一夜之间解决所有问题
Gen. Zhivkovich is on it. You can't solve everything overnight.
你的椅子不舒服，小心别弄丢了
Your chair is uncomfortable. Be careful not to lose it.
警察会找到凶手的，调查还在进行中
The police will find the killer. The investigation is ongoing.
如果我们早点过来，人们就不会踩到证据了
Had we arrived on time, people wouldn't be stepping on evidence now.
这是什么，日沃因？
What have we got here, Zhivoyin?
你自己看吧，长官
See for yourself, inspector.
”来自Tatko的问候”
"Greetings from Tatko"
确实是很好的问候
Nice greeting, indeed...
博什科·塔蒂亚娜-Tatko
Boshko Tatich - Tatko.
这不就是你被调离的那个案子吗？
Wasn't that the case you've been taken from?
没错，现在谁负责？
That's right. Who's on it now?
- 托米奇探长 - 该死
- Inspector Tomich. - Damn it...
打扰一下，你能记录一下吗？
Excuse me... Could you please write this down?
这些伤口显然是一时冲动造成的
The wounds were clearly inflicted in the heat of the moment.
共有六处伤口
There are six wounds.
四处是死前造成的
Four were inflicted before death,
死后还有两处伤口
and two after.
在我拿到指纹之前请不要碰任何东西，谢谢
Please, do not touch anything before I get the prints. Thank you.
哦，现在我明白了，你是个莱斯男孩！
Oh, now I get it. You're a Reissboy!
是的，我很荣幸能从
Yes, I had a privilege to graduate from
阿奇博尔德 · 莱斯警察学校毕业
Dr. Archibald Reiss' police school.
我在洛桑获得了法医学博士学位
And I earned a PhD in forensics in Lausanne.
还忘了怎么说塞尔维亚语
And forgot your Serbian.
写下来: 胸部有六处刺伤
Write this down: Six stab wounds to the chest.
没有找到武器
Weapon was not recovered.
尸体解剖会揭示其余的部分
The autopsy will reveal the rest.
你忘了"来自Tatko的问候"
You forgot the greetings from Tatko.
我问你什么了吗？
Did I ask you something?
盖上尸体，等待病理学家过来
Cover that body and wait for pathologists.
要不要我也给你拿点喝的？
Would you like me to get you a drink too?
我看得出你清醒的时候脾气很暴躁
I can see you're grumpy when you're sober.
- 他刚才说什么? - 我不知道
- What did he just say? - I don't know.
探长，我该让他们进来吗？
Inspector, should I let them in?
好像你能拦住他们似的
As if you could stop them.
上校，早上的仪式取消了
Colonel, the morning service has been cancelled.
这里躺着我们的兄弟
Here lies our brother.
死了，被谋杀了
Dead. Murdered.
你调查清楚了吗？到底发生了什么事？
What do you have to tell me? What happened?
你的兄弟，一位诚实的牧师
What did your brother, an honest priest,
和已故的博什科·塔蒂亚娜，也就是Tatko有什么关系？
have to do with the late Boshko Tatich, aka "Tatko"?
没有，我甚至不知道那是谁
None. I don't even know who that is.
真的吗？
Really?
你不知道"Tatko"？
You don't know who Tatko is,
但你声称神父与他无关
but you claim the priest had nothing to do with him.
祭坛下面有什么东西吗？
Was there something in the altar?
怎么，你发现了什么？
Why, you found something?
不，不，只是问问
No, no. Just asking.
我注意到它坏了，所以我想知道这是不是又一次报复
I noticed it's broken, so I wondered if it wasn't another act of revenge.
上校？
Colonel?
让他们带人离开这里
Tell them to take their men out of here,
我们来接手我们土地上的调查
and let us take over the investigation on our land.
这是我们的土地，年轻人，只有教堂是你们的
This is my land, young man. Only the church is yours.
你什么时候完成犯罪现场调查？
When will you finish the crime scene investigation?
我不知道...如果不是某些可疑人物干扰了我的调查
I can't tell... It would probably go faster,
也许会更快一些
if some dubious characters weren't messing with my investigation.
布科沃村，马其顿，南斯拉夫王国
Bukovo village, Macedonia, Kingdom of Yugoslavia
特纳瓦茨，谁是接替Tatko的新老板？
Trnavatz, who's the new boss that replaced Tatko?
我不知道，没人见过他
I don't know. Nobody saw him.
- 真可怕 - 的确可怕
- That's scary. - Scary, indeed.
好酒！
Damn, this is good...
从提克维什来的没受过洗礼
From Tikvesh. Non-baptized.
货物呢? 受洗了吗？
And the goods? Were they baptised?
不，我们举行了葬礼
No. We had a funeral.
- 这次是什么病? - 肺结核
What was it this time? Tuberculosis.
又来? 想想别的吧
Again? Think of something else, Jesus.
你想怎么样，告诉警察你奶奶死于梅毒？
What do you want, to tell the police that your grandma died from syphilis?
帮我拿着这个，替我向基拉问好
Hold this for me. Say hi to Kyro for me.
嘿，孩子，过来！
Hey, kid, come here!
”确定审判 IMRO 恐怖分子达米安·哈吉·阿尔索夫的日期”
"Trial date set for the IMRO terrorist Damyan Hadgy Arsov"
- 我想发个电报 - 好的
- I'd like to send a telegram, please. - Yes.
你的衣服准备好了，来试试吧，阿廖沙
Your suit is ready. Come to try it. Alyosha.
地址？
Address?
苏联 莫斯科总部
OGPU Headquarters Moscow, USSR
你的衣服准备好了 来试试吧 阿廖沙
Your suit is ready. Come to try it. Alyosha.
门辛斯基同志，我来报到
Comrade Menzhinsky. I'm reporting for duty.
少校，贝尔津同志推荐了你
Major, comrade Berzin recommended you.
他表扬了你..
He praised you...
但我不认为把你送到贝尔格莱德是正确的决定
but I'm not sure that sending you to Belgrade is the right solution.
塞萨洛尼基
The Thessaloniki process,
黑手党
the Black Hand,
卡拉乔杰维奇国王都在悬赏要你的人头
King Karadjordjevich is offering a reward for your head.
整个巴尔干半岛的人都知道... 谁是穆斯塔法 · 戈卢比奇
The whole Balkans know... who is Mustapha Golubich.
他们可能会逮捕我，我甚至可能会死
They may arrest me, I might even die,
但我一定会完成任务
but surely not before I finish my assignment.
这是我们在贝尔格莱德的特工报告
These are the reports from our agents in Belgrade.
这里是你的任务的细节
Here are the details of your mission.
阅后即焚
Burn after reading.
把他弄出来！
Get him out!
把他放在这儿！
Put him here!
- 是这儿吗? - 嗯？
- Is it here? - Huh?
- 是不是这儿? - 是的
- Is it here!? - Yes.
把他放回去
Put him back.
不，求你了..
No, please...
斯塔夫拉，约旦，多布里沃伊，我们要这么做，看..
Stavra, Yordan, Dobrivoye, here's what we're gonna do, look...
太挤了，上车，回去！
It's too crowded. Get in the car. Back up!
我很快就回来
I won't be long.
科萨？出去吧
Kosa? Leave us.
但为什么呢？
But why?
欢迎加入我们
Feel free to join us.
科萨
Kosa.
我们成功了，成功阻止了他们
We did it. We blocked them.
- 裁缝店 - 任务完成了吗？
- Tailor shop. - Did you finish the job?
那个有钱的姑娘招待检察官，也许我应该去拜访一下她
That rich girl entertains prosecutors, maybe I should pay her a visit.
- 不，现在还不行 - 好吧
- No, not yet. - Okay.
- 抓住那个摄影师 - 我会的
- Squeeze that photographer. - I will.
可怜的人，他还没僵硬呢
Poor man. He's not even stiff yet.
你可以在他还软弱的时候开始
Well, you can start while he's still soft.
我不敢，巴比奇会生气的
I'm not sure. Babich will get mad.
别担心他，谁知道他在哪里，开始吧
Don't worry about him. God knows where he is. Go ahead.
如果你坚持的话
If you insist.
这位新伙伴叫什么名字？
And what's the name of our new mate?
斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇警官
Stanko Pletikosich. Inspector Stanko Pletikosich.
她指的是躺在这的伙伴
She meant the dead mate.
哦，他，安东 · 尼钦斯基，64岁，牧师
Oh, him. Anton Nizhinsky, 64 years old, clergyman.
谢谢，我是博雅娜 · 安提奇，巴比奇博士的实习生
Thanks. I'm Boyana Antich, an intern for Dr. Babich.
- 很高兴认识你 - 我也是
- Pleased to meet you. - Me too.
别费心记住他的名字，他过几天就会辞职的
Don't bother remembering his name. He'll quit in couple of days.
不然就是因为那件外套被捅死
Or he'll get stabbed for that coat.
对不对，奥地利小子？
Isn't that right, Austrian boy?
- 洛桑在瑞士 - 不会吧？
- Lausanne is in Switzerland. - You don't say.
请不要被杀，否则我会像这样剥了你的衣服
Please don't get killed. I'd have to strip you like this.
那样的话，我很乐意去死
In that case, I would be my pleasure to die.
别拿这个开玩笑，脱衣服是最难的部分
Don't joke about that. Stripping is the hardest part.
- 比如把最后一块去掉 - 谁让你碰顾客的？
- Like removing the last bits. - Who told you to touch the customer?
你到底去哪儿了? 你总是说没有工作,
Where the heck have you been? You're always saying there's no work,
- 我带来工作了你却不在 - 咖啡和糖呢？
- and when I bring some you're gone. - Where's the coffee, the sweets?
你要让我空着肚子工作吗？
Am I supposed to work on an empty stomach?
什么情况？
What have we got here?
一位俄罗斯牧师在教堂被杀害，地上写着来自"Tatko"的问候
A Russian priest killed at the church. And greetings from Tatko.
还记得塔蒂奇吗？
Remember Tatich?
我怎么能忘记他呢? 我像切小牛肉一样切他
How could I forget him? I cut him like veal.
他们把你调离了那个案子对吧？
They took you off that case, right?
当我开始怀疑俄国人的时候
When I started suspecting the Russians.
不好意思，我能不能问问你..
Excuse me, if I could just ask you...
你知道我在想什么吗? "Tatko"的人有理由报复
You know what I'm thinking? Tatko's men had a reason to retaliate.
对于他们来说，俄罗斯人扼杀了他们的生意
With Tatko, the Russians killed their business.
我敢说他们的生意正在蓬勃发展
I'd say their business is blooming.
还在抽鸦片吗？
Still taking some?
一周几次，这样我可以做爱时间更长
Few times a week, so I can fuck longer.
但是现在，马其顿的东西到处都是
But now, you have Macedonian stuff on every corner.
而且质量上乘
And it's top quality.
这意味着有人接管了生意
That means someone has taken over the business.
对不起，我问你一件事，你是巴比奇教授吗？
Excuse me, let me ask you something. You are professor Babich?
- 这家伙是谁? - 这不重要..
- Who the hell is this guy? - It doesn't matter...
我是斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇，你年轻的同事
I'm Stanko Pletikosich. Your younger colleague.
见到你是我的荣幸
It is an honour to meet you.
我过去常引用你早期的一些论文
I used to quote some of your early papers.
给你
There you go.
谢谢，现在坐下来写报告吧
Thanks. Now sit down and write.
在情绪激动时造成的刺伤
Stab wounds inflicted in the heat of passion.
首先是胃，其他是随机伤口
First to the stomach, others randomly,
没那么有力，可能是在恐慌中
less forcefully, probably in a panic.
没有自卫伤，这意味着牧师是一个真正的基督徒
No self-defence wounds, meaning the priest was a true Christian.
也可能是他认识凶手？
Or maybe he knew the killer?
死亡发生在五到五个半小时之前
Death occurred between five and five and a half hours ago.
报告完毕
End of report.
真可耻! 你忘了你的礼貌了吗？
Shame on you! Have you forgotten your manners?
我们很抱歉把你从床上叫起来，尼古拉 · 彼得罗维奇
We apologise for getting you out of bed, Nikolay Petrovich.
我没有太多时间，所以我长话短说
I don't have much time, so I will keep it short.
谁在我们的教堂里筑了祭坛？
Who built the altar in our church?
我需要他们的名字，地址，所有你知道的关于他们的信息！
I need names, addresses, everything you have on them!
你为什么像个傻瓜一样把我拖到这儿来？
Why did you drag me over here like a sack?
安东 · 尼钦斯基神父昨晚在教堂被残忍地杀害了
Father Anton was brutally murdered. Last night, at the church.
亲爱的上帝
Dear God.
所有知道祭坛里有什么的人
Everyone who knew what was in the altar
都在这个房间里
is in this room right now.
我们宣过誓的
We are under oath.
但你没有，卡斯诺夫先生
But you're not, Mister Krasnov.
你有没有和什么人提起过？
Have you mentioned it in front of some worker?
你认为我会向别人透露
You think I would reveal where the last reminder
我们堕落帝国最后的希望在哪里？
and hope of our fallen empire is?
先生们，你们最好自己去找那个叛徒！
Better look for the traitor amongst yourselves, gentlemen!
你到底想干什么，和你一起工作的都是些什么人渣？
What are you up to, and what sort of scum are you working with?
如果是你的肮脏勾当害死了安东神父
If your dirty business killed father Anton,
弗兰格尔将军会知道的
General Vrangel will know of it.
不管怎样，弗兰格尔将军都会知道的，我会告诉他的
Vrangel will know of it anyway. I will tell him.
给我所有泥瓦匠和肖像画家的名字,
Give me the names of all the masons, iconographers,
还有建造教堂的工匠，马上！
and craftsmen who built the church. Now!
费奥多，我不在的时候你来指挥
Fyodor, you will replace me while I'm gone.
你知道该怎么做
You'll know what to do.
最重要的是找到凶手
The most important thing is to find the murderer.
找到凶手也就找回了我们最后的希望
When you do, you'll know where the treasure is.
我们必须在警察之前找到他
We have to find him before the police does.
那个检查官不是我们的人
That inspector is not one of us.
我们在警察局有足够的人手
We have enough of our men in the police.
他们很清楚应该先通知我们
They know very well they should inform us first.
兄弟们，祝我好运吧
Brothers, wish me good luck.
上帝保佑你，瓦西里·彼得罗维奇
God bless you, Vasiliy Petrovich.
不惜一切代价抓到凶手
Find the thief, whatever it takes.
- 去布鲁塞尔要多久? - 一天
- How long will it take to Brussels? - One day.
你只有一天时间
You have one day.
近一点，再近一点！
Closer. A bit closer!
苏联 列宁山庄
LENINZ'S HILL VILLAGE USSR
向我们的阿廖沙同志微笑
Smile for our comrade Alyosha.
打扰一下... 我能再问一个问题吗？
Excuse me... May I ask one more question?
医生说的马其顿的东西到底是什么？
What exactly did the doctor mean by Macedonian stuff?
塞尔维亚南部最著名的产品是什么？
What's the most famous product from southern Serbia?
我想你说的应该不是辣椒粉
I guess you don't mean paprika.
罂粟? 鸦片？
Poppy? Opium?
Tatko曾经在贝尔格莱德卖鸦片
Tatko used to sell it in Belgrade.
直到他越过俄罗斯来卖土耳其鸦片
Until he crossed the Russians. They sell Turkish opium.
但是不要在局长面前这么说
But don't say that in front of the Commissioner.
为什么马其顿人会因为鸦片而杀死一个牧师？
Why would the Macedonians kill a priest because of opium?
我不知道，别说了，好吗？
I don't know. Stop talking now, would you?
斯韦塔
Sveta
督察，局长在等你
Inspector, the commissioner is waiting for you.
我听说俄罗斯牧师的案子在你手上! 甩不掉了，是吧？
I heard you got the Russian priest! Can't get them off your back, huh?
我需要码头突袭Tatko的报告
I need the report from the raid on the docks. Tatko's gang.
为什么? 这是鸦片，走私！
What for, man? It's opium, smuggling!
就看一眼
Just a peek.
塔尼，我给你带了咖啡
Tane, I brought you coffee.
你是唯一照顾我的人
You're the only one taking care of me.
上帝保佑你，塔尼，他真的很喜欢如栅阿姨,
God bless you, Tane. He really likes Auntie Ruzha,
不像其他人他们连看都不看我一眼
unlike some other people. They don't even look at me.
我是新来的斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇，技术警察
I'm your new colleague Stanko Pletikosich, Technical police.
很高兴见到你，这个部门太糟糕了
Pleased to meet you. This department is awful.
我调到走私和诈骗部去了
I ran away into smuggling and fraud.
这是你的办公室
So this is your office.
接下来要做什么？我们去追查Tatko帮派？
What's next, we go after Tatko's gang?
我想这张桌子应该没人用吧
I suppose this desk is unoccupied.
拉佐，把钥匙给我
Lazo, give me the key.
督察，我只带了六磅油! 放了我们吧！
Inspector, it was just six pounds of oil! Let us go!
警官! 那个人死了! 他咳了两个星期的血！
Officer! That one's dead! He coughed blood for two weeks!
- 那又怎样? - 什么意思? ！
- So what? - What do you mean?!
把他拖出去！
Get him the hell outta here!
你觉得他会死而复生吗? 退后！
You think he'll rise from the dead? Back off!
探长，我问你，他是你的表弟吗？
Inspector, let me ask you something. Is he some cousin of yours?
米利萨夫，把钥匙给我
Milisav, give me those keys.
然后滚远一点
And go fuck yourself.
明白
Understood.
你这个白痴，他们会宰了你的
You moron, they'll shoot you like a dog.
他们宣布你是恐怖分子,
They declared you a terrorist,
国王和国家的敌人！
an enemy of the King and the country!
该死
Bloody hell.
我可能有办法，但你得合作
I may have a solution. But you'll have to cooperate.
你必须合作
But you'll have to cooperate.
- 你不认识我吗，塔尼? - 如果你都不想帮自己
- Don't you know me, Tane? - How can I help you
那我还能帮你做什么呢？
if you don't want to help yourself?
如果你合作，我可以和一些人谈谈
If you cooperate, I could talk to some people.
有些人并没有忘记你在战争中的所作所为
Some of us didn't forget what you did in the war.
跟警察合作又能怎么样？
And how would that cooperation with your policemen look like?
今天早上一名牧师在俄罗斯教堂被杀害
A priest was killed in the Russian church this morning.
地上用血写着: “来自 Tatko 的问候”
The message said: "Greetings from Tatko".
那又怎样? 我和他有什么关系？
So? What do I have to do with him?
别告诉我你认为我是毒贩子？
Don't tell me you think I'm a drug mule?
少废话，Tatko 和一些乡下人一起工作过
Cut the crap. Tatko worked with some of countrymen...
啊，你认为我会告密？
Ah, you think I'm a rat?
如果俄国人在我之前找到凶手，你会很后悔没告诉我
If the Russians find them before I do, you'll be sorry you didn't rat.
当他们找到凶手的时候，会被折磨得生不如死
And when they do find them, they'll regret being born.
这样的话，我可能会后悔救了你的命，塔尼
The way things are, I'll probably regret saving your life, Tane.
我们有足够的时间去后悔
We had enough time to regret that.
我们俩都是
Both of us.
看看我们，塔尼，两个死人，空壳
Look at us, Tane. Two dead men. Empty shells.
那个该死的陀思妥耶夫斯基让你很沮丧
That fucking Dostoyevsky is making you depressed.
你得到你想要的了，我的朋友，不是吗？
You got what you wanted, my friend, didn't you?
有三个名字的人得到了国家
The folk with three names got their country.
那我们呢？
And what about us?
我们是塞尔维亚人吗? 克罗地亚人? 还是斯洛文尼亚人？
Are we Serbs? Croats? Slovenes?
都不是！我们的国家在哪里，塔尼？
We're not! Where's our country, Tane?
不要给扯这些政治话题！
Don't give me your political tirades!
告诉我你想要什么
Tell me what you want.
我想要个灯和一条干净的毯子
I want a lantern and a clean blanket.
还想洗个澡
And I want a bath.
- 就这样? - 不是
- Is that it? - No.
我需要一个律师，一个会来这里看我的律师
I want a lawyer. One that will visit me here
让我可以准备辩护策略
so we can prepare a defence strategy.
写下他的名字: 安特 · 帕维里奇
Write down his name: Ante Pavelich.
很好
Good.
如果我失败了，我不会使用这些信息
I won't use that information if I fail.
我向你保证
You have my word.
安德拉 · 塔纳西耶维奇，一个守信用的人
Andra Tanasiyevich, a man of his word.
听我说，我不想在你和那个荡妇身上浪费时间
Listen to me. I don't have time for you and that slut.
无论如何你都得拿到那些照片
You're gonna get those pictures one way or the other,
否则我就把你的蛋蛋割下来，明白吗？
or I'll have your balls cut off. Got it?
求你了，不要
Please, don't.
太晚了! 你拍照片的时候想啥了
Too late! You should've whined when you were getting stock on tick
还在两个不同的地方卖那些同性恋的照片
and selling those faggot pictures in two different places.
你怎么不组织一场拍卖会！
You should've organised an auction while at it!
给他一点！
Give him some!
这样…
Look here...
我可以饶了你
I'll forgive your debts.
当你把照片给我的时候，也许还会给你一个额外的奖励
When you bring me the pictures. And maybe give you an extra treat.
谁要加入，孩子们? 想跟他玩玩吗？
Who's in, kids? Wanna blow his arse?
不，老板，他不是我喜欢的类型
No boss, he's not my type.
- 哦，你喜欢什么类型的? - 斯马会喜欢的
- Oh you have a type? - Sima will do it.
我不喜欢，他们没牙齿
I don't like them toothless.
老板，我来安排吉普赛人帮派
Boss, I'll arrange a gangbang with our gypsies.
很好，我喜欢
Deal. I like that.
现在是我们限制了他们
Now it's us who blocked them.
他们只需要解除限制
They just need to unblock us.
- 说起来容易做起来难 - 交给我吧
- Easier said than done. - Leave that to me.
我告诉过你不要单独行动
I told you not to do anything on your own.
- 别惹日瓦科维奇将军-为什么？
- Don't mess with General Zhivkovich. - Why?
我知道他不喜欢女人，但我觉得我应该试试..
I know he doesn't like women, but I thought I should try...
国王都看他颜色行事
Even the King dances to his tune.
- 国王? - 国王..
- The King? - The King...
你疯了吗，他随时会回来的
Are you mad, he'll be here any second.
没有你我活不下去
I can't live without you.
谁让你动我东西的？
Who told you to touch this?
太乱了，我简单收拾一下
It was too messy, I had to tidy up.
你凭什么收拾我的桌子? 你爸妈怎么教育你的？
Who are you to tidy up my desk? Who the fuck raised you?
如果我的父母还活着，我会很生气，但是他们在一战中被杀了
I'd get mad if my parents were alive, but they were killed in the Great war.
- 对不起 - 没关系
- I'm sorry. - It's okay.
这样我怎么找东西
How am I gonna find my stuff now...
给你，塔尼，整个案子的档案
Here you go, Tane. The entire case file.
督察，我已经把这个柜子里的所有文件都整理好了
Inspector, I've arranged all the files in this cabinet.
托米奇，告诉我报告里面没有什么
Tomich, tell me what's not in here.
谁接替了 Tatko？
Who succeeded Tatko?
没有人知道是谁，我们只知道有人接管了公司
Nobody knows who he is, all we know is that he took over.
- 而且存货比以往任何时候都多 - 我听说了
- And has more stock than ever. - So I've heard.
显然，这次突袭毫无意义
Apparently, the raid was for nothing.
也许是那个新老板下令谋杀神父的？
Maybe that new boss ordered the priest's murder?
作为报复
As a retaliation.
谁是巴塞尔·特纳瓦茨？
And who is Basyl Trnavatz?
- 你怎么知道他的? - 说吧
- How do you know about him? - Come on, speak.
塔尼，请告诉我有关 Tatko 那伙人的任何消息
Tane please, tell me anything you have on Tatko's gang.
- 我追踪他们好几个月了 - 追踪到哪里？
- I've been chasing them for months. - Chasing where?
有消息说他们在亚塔汉贫民窟
Well... I'm chasing the information. I heard they're in Yataghan slum.
所以你知道他们在哪里，但你不敢去
So you know where they are, but you don't dare going there.
我们人手不够! 而且我对付不了那帮人渣
I never have enough officers! And I can't handle that scum.
多布里沃伊怎么样？
What about Dobrivoye?
他只是个恶棍，特纳瓦茨很重要
He's just a thug. Trnavac is important.
他是马其顿人的联系人
He's the link with Macedonians.
很可能就是运货的那个
And probably the one bringing in the goods.
督察，局长让我带你和那孩子去办公室
Inspector, the commissioner told me to bring you and the kid over.
如果你拒绝，我将不得不逮捕你
If you refuse I'll have to arrest you.
电话响了一整天了！
It's been ringing all day!
每个人都骑在我头上
Everyone's been sitting on my back!
俄国人，我们的人，部长，官员，所有的混蛋
The Russians, our people, ministers, officials, every bastard out there.
谁杀了牧师，他们为什么要杀他，Tatko 有参与吗？
Who killed the priest, why they killed him, is Tatko involved?
整个城市都疯了
The whole city has went mad over this.
- 我不知道自己在想什么 - 好像你曾经想过似的
- I don't know where my head's at. - As if you ever did.
真有趣
How funny.
如果 Tatko 的人在追杀俄国人，那一定会有伤亡
If Tatko's men are after the Russians, there will be blood.
- 找到凶手 - 我会的
- Find the killer. - I will.
但我需要你先做这件事
But I need you to do this first.
这是什么？
What is it?
又是你的那个战友？
That wartime buddy of yours again?
不仅仅是我的战友，还是一位战争英雄
Not just my friend, but a war hero.
如果是马其顿人干的，他会把一切都告诉我
If the Macedonians did it, he'll give me everything.
我们先满足他的要求
Let's give him what he wants.
我得问问检察长
I'll have to ask the prosecutor.
他想让安特 · 帕维里奇做他的律师
He wants Ante Pavelich to be his lawyer.
做梦吧
That's not gonna work.
我要去小巴雷尔家吃点豆子
I'm off to the Little Barrell for some beans.
等等，我会告诉你结果的，你觉得那个孩子怎么样？
Hold on, wait. I'll let you know. What do you think about the kid?
有点没用，但我遇到过更糟的
He's sort of useless but I've had worse.
你从哪儿弄到这个的？
Where did you get this?
别在意那些，亲爱的
It doesn't matter, love.
重要的是我已经不是以前的我了
What matters is that I'm a different man now.
我现在是有钱人，我们可以在一起了
A wealthy man. We can be together now.
你知道这是不可能的
You know that's not possible.
一切皆有可能
Anything is possible.
我已经把一切都计划好了
I have everything planned out.
我们搬去巴黎
We'll live in Paris.
等我们安顿下来，我父母就会过来
And when we get settled, my parents will come over.
我明天戴着它想你
I'll wear it tomorrow and think of you.
不，绝对不行! 你绝对不能在这里戴它！
No, never! You should never wear it here!
对不起，请原谅我
I'm sorry, forgive me, forgive me...
你知道人们会好奇的..
You know people are inquisitive...
他们会注意到并开始问问题
They'll notice and start asking questions.
好吧，我摘下来
Alright, I'll take it off.
你可以在巴黎戴着
You'll wear it in Paris.
- 他回来了，快走，快点! - 项链藏起来！
- He's back. Go away, go! Faster! - Hide it!
- 你快走，快点! - 藏好！
维奥莉特，你在吗？
Violet, are you there?
睡着了吗？
Are you sleeping?
- 我还要等多久?-我们永远不知道
- How long would I wait? - That we never know.
久基奇，过来
Djukich, come here.
什么事这么急？
What's so urgent?
是关于那个俄国牧师的谋杀案
It's about the murder of that Russian priest.
我完全没有头绪
I'm completely lost.
你想让我帮你？
And you want me to solve it for you, huh?
说吧
Hit me, Michko.
格拉夫尼亚查 监狱里的那个恐怖分子..
That terrorist in Glavnyacha prison...
哈吉 · 阿尔索夫，对吗？
Haji Arsov, right?
他能给我们提供一些有用的信息
He can give us some useful information.
那件谋杀案必须马上破案
That murder has to be solved right away.
我最不需要的就是和俄国人发生冲突
The last thing I need is a conflict with the Russians.
他想要什么回报？
What the fuck does he want in return?
他已经准备好接受审判了，但他想要自己的律师
He's set for trial. He wants his own lawyer.
- 律师? - 安特 · 帕维里奇
- A lawyer? - Ante Pavelich.
有意思
Interesting.
好吧
Alright.
- 批准了 - 批准了？
- Approved. - Approved?
内文！
Neven!
发生了什么？
What happened?
来吧，进来
C'mon, get in.
兹维塔，马上把这个给帕皮
Tzveta, take this to Papi right away.
老板，你今天来得真早
You're early this morning, Boss.
当他开始抱怨的时候，告诉他一切都结束了
When he starts whining, tell him it's over.
与股东之间的战争还将继续
The war with the shareholders will continue.
- 玛雅，这是... ? - 是的，他们一分钱也得不到
- Maya, is this...? - Yes, they won't take another cent.
- 终于来了! - 快去
- Finally! - Come on. Get it.
谁把你打成那样
Who disfigured you like that
又是因为鸦片吗？
Was it opium again?
你需要多少钱？
Tell me how much money you need.
我不需要钱，我需要底片
I don't need money. I need the negatives.
你把我的照片给别人了？
You offered my negatives to someone?
我别无选择，玛雅
I had no choice, Maya.
我为那些照片付了你黄金，你这个变态！
I gave you pure gold for those photos, you sick prick!
玛雅，他们把我打得半死，看看我..
Maya, they kicked the crap out of me, look at me...
他们需要多少钱
How much money do they need to forget about you,
才能忘记你和底片？
about the negatives and that they've ever heard of them?
如果你欺骗我，愿你的灵魂被诅咒
May your soul be cursed if you trick me.
我已经没有灵魂了，我告诉他们底片在你这
I don't have a soul anymore. I told them you have them.
出去
Get out.
- 玛雅 - 我再也不想见到你了
- Maya... - I don't ever want to see you again.
- 我只是想... - 另一扇门，笨蛋
- I just wanted... - To the other side, dumbhead
- 好久不见 维奥莱塔 你好吗? - 你好
- Hell, Violet. How are you? - Hi there.
女士们，先生们，亲爱的朋友们，现如今作为一名捐助者..
Ladies and gentlemen, dear friends. Being a benefactor today...
被认为是一种神圣的行为
is considered a sacred act.
多亏了一个人，我们整个医院
Thanks to one man, an entire wing of our hospital
都被翻新了
has been renovated
并且还从这个人的工厂
and, we got a large donation of medicines
获得了大量捐赠的药品
from his own factory.
女士们，先生们，有请阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇先生
Ladies and gentlemen, Mr. Alimpiye Mirich.
谢谢，阿瓦库莫维奇医生
Thank you, Dr. Avakumovich.
就像伟大的约翰·洛克菲勒曾经说过的那样:
Like the great John Rockefeller once said:
“如果你在做正确的事情,
"If you're doing the right thing,
”应该让正确的人知道”
let the right people know about it".
现在你们都知道了
And here you are.
我想了很久，不知道该为这家医院
I thought long and hard to choose the right words
重新开业致什么词
for the opening of this hospital,
但归根结底还是:
but it all comes down to:
愿你永远不需要来这里
May you never need it.
也就是说，我正式宣布医院开业
That said, I officially declare the hospital open.
祝贺你！
Congratulations!
亲爱的，你真可爱! 那个乡巴佬是谁？
My love, you were so cute! And who's that bumpkin?
- 沃因·久基奇先生 - 新上任的国家检察官！
- Mr. Voyin Djukich. - The new state prosecutor!
- 我听说你干得不错 - 这么说吧，我心怀正义
- I heard you're doing a great job. - Let's just say I care about justice.
难怪，我在日瓦科维奇将军家见过你
No wonder I met you at general Zhivkovich's,
安全部门以其正义感而闻名
The Security service is well-known for its sense of justice.
这位是沃因 · 久基奇的妻子维奥莱塔
Voyin Djukich's wife, Violeta.
还有我亲爱的克丽丝塔
And my dear Krista.
女士们，我听说过你们的仁慈性情
My ladies, I've heard of your benevolent dispositions,
但是却不知道你们如此美丽动人
but your beauty was kept secret!
你以为只有丑女人才是善良的吗？
You think only ugly women are kind?
阿瓦库莫维奇夫人，你真聪明！
Mrs. Avakumovich, you are even smarter!
维奥莱特，你看起来容光焕发
Violet, you look radiant.
- 那条项链真漂亮 - 谢谢
- That necklace is wonderful. - Thanks.
哦，拜托，我都快被闪瞎了
Oh please, I nearly went blind by looking at it.
- 我能看看吗? - 当然
- May I take a look? - Of course.
那么，维奥莱特，这项链你花了多少钱？
So, Voyin, how much did it cost you?
他拿到账单的时候就知道了，我自己买的
He'll know when he gets the check. I bought it myself.
你在哪里买的？
And where did you buy it?
我不记得了，在一家古董店里
I don't remember. In an antique shop.
- 恭喜你 - 这是件珍贵的东西
- Congratulations. - It's a precious piece.
玛雅! 玛雅来了
Maya! Here's Maya.
- 我就知道你会迟到 - 大家下午好
- I knew you'd be late. - Good afternoon, everyone.
你穿着这么透的裙子是不是冻僵了？
Aren't you freezing in that tiny dress?
我宁愿把它脱掉，但那样不合适
I'd rather take it off, but that would be inappropriate.
穿不穿没什么两样
No one would notice the difference.
让我来介绍一下
Let me introduce you.
阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇先生，这位是玛雅·达维多维奇
Mr. Alimpiye Mirich. Maya Davidovich.
- 很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- Pleased to meet you. - Likewise.
阿里姆皮耶先生是我们最慷慨的捐赠者
Mr. Alimpiye is our most generous donor.
当然
After you, of course.
你应该来参加军官俱乐部的假面舞会
You should come to the costume ball at the Officer's club.
不用费心去找服装了，这身衣服就不错
Don't bother searching for a costume, this will do it.
谢谢你，我会代你向我的裁缝问好的
Thank you, I will give your regards to my tailor.
不幸的是，我不得不谢绝你的邀请
Unfortunately, I have to decline your invitation.
我有一些紧急的事情要处理
I've got some urgent matters to sort out.
别生气，先生
Don't get angry, sir.
玛雅真的很在乎衣服
Maya really cares about clothing.
她的服装总是最好的
Her costumes are always the best.
我真的得走了，医生，你能送我一下吗？
Well, I really have to get going. Doctor, will you escort me?
好的，当然
Yes, certainly.
希望能再见到你
Hope I'll see you again.
私下里
Alone.
我们去喝一杯吧
Let's go have a drink.
也许我也应该穿成那样？
Maybe I should be original too?
督察，迪米特里耶维奇局长找你
Inspector, Commissioner Dimitriyevich asks for you.
我来了
I'm coming.
督察，迪米特里耶维奇局长找你
Inspector, Commissioner Dimitriyevich asks for you.
他除了找我还做过别的事吗？
Does he ever do anything else?
你告诉他局长在找他了吗？
Have you told him about the commissioner?
是的
Yes.
我昨天一整天都在帮你处理那件事
I spent all day yesterday trying to fix that thing for you,
然而你却现在才来上班？
and you're coming to work at this hour?
拿着这个！
Take this!
你朋友有律师了
Your mate got his lawyer.
干得好! 可别耍他
Well done! Don't fuck him over now.
别搞砸了，快点找出凶手
Don't you fuck it up now. Question him and find the killer.
把这个放到我的桌子上
Take this to my desk
叫如栅把我的帽子擦干净
and ask Ruzha to clean my hat.
- 我们要去哪里? - 亚塔汉贫民窟
- Where are we going? - To Yataghan slum.
- 去过那里吗? - 没有
- Ever been there? - No.
你这样去可不行，把鞋子擦干净
You can't go like that. Wipe those shoes please.
你有多少子弹？
How many bullets do you have?
我连枪都没有
I don't even have a gun yet.
该死
Oh, fuck.
别在那杵着，跟我走
Stop gawking around. Eyes ahead.
- 嘿，长官! - 下午好，女士们..
- Hey, inspector! - Afternoon, ladies...
那孩子是谁? 他今天带老二出门了吗？
Who's the kid? D'he bring his prick?
- 我替他带了 - 过来帅哥！
- I brought it for him. - Come over here, handsome!
来吧，给我五块钱我就让你看看我的宝贝！
C'mon, I'll show you my thing for a fiver!
我只收三块钱！
Over here, I'll give you mine for three!
啊，长官！
Ay, inspector!
来喝点肉汤吧！
Come grab some broth!
你好吗，格济姆？
How are you, Gezym?
你去哪儿了？
Where've you been?
你消失了很久！
You disappeared like a loaf of bread!
我以为你离开警察局了
Thought you left the force.
我想离开它，但它离不开我
I'd leave it, but it won't leave me.
这小子是谁？
Who's the clown?
我的表弟，从乡下来的
My cousin. From the countryside.
- 表弟? - 不是，不好意思我是..
- A cousin? - No, no, excuse me, I'm a...
一个表弟
A cousin.
记住他的脸，他来的时候你帮我罩着点
Remember his face. Watch over him when he comes here.
我会的
I will.
你去哪儿了，莫德林? 还在私酿法国酒吗？
Where've you been, Maudlin? Still have that French moonshine?
没有，我们的酿酒厂被烧毁了
Nope. Our distillery burnt down.
但是你来的话，我们有上好的
But for you, we'll get the original.
该死，格济姆，买点鱼吧，不能用土豆做鱼汤
Damn, Gezym, buy some fish. Can't make a fish broth from potatoes.
你是个警察，但你是个好人
You're a cop, but a damn good man too.
我总是告诉我的人: 那些警察都是混蛋,
I always tell my men: Them coppers are all assholes,
但还是有好人的
but sometimes an honest guy pops up.
- 忙什么呢，尼什基? - 在处理行政事务
- What's up, Nishky? - Tryin' to cope with administration.
- 你还能处理什么? - 处理那些人渣，伙计
- What else do you cope with? - With the scum, man.
但也许有一天当你们警察意识到贝尔格莱德
But you coppers will handle that one day...
不仅仅是市中心的时候，就不用我处理了
When you realise there's more to Belgrade's than the city centre.
是啊，投诉吧
Yeah, file a complaint.
为什么? 你厕纸用完了？
Why? You ran out of toilet paper?
这个国家不是由国王统治的,
Man, this country ain't ruled by the king,
或者军队，或者警察，而是通过官僚机构？
or the army, or the police, but by bureaucracy?
- 是真的吗? - 是的
- Is that true? - It is.
我想把这个地方命名为“ Inn Nish”
I wanted to name this place "Inn Nish",
但是他们说语法不正确！
but they said it was grammatically incorrect!
我的意思是，拜托! ？
I mean, c'mon!?
我得贿赂遇到的任何人,
I have to bribe anyone I run into,
他们还想让我学贝尔格莱德语法？
and they still want me to take up a Belgrade accent?
这小子是谁？
And who the hell is this guy?
一个新同事
A new colleague.
真的吗? 你们这些警察真的太随便了
Really? You coppers really are taking a piss.
嘿，你，你想喝点什么？
Hey you, what do you want to drink?
你们有什么酒？
What sort of wine do you have?
红的和白的
The red sort and the white sort.
我要红酒，还有一杯水，谢谢
I'll have the red. And a glass of water. Thank you.
要不给你整杯西瓜汁？
And maybe a watermelon with that?
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
- 我是来吃饭的 - 出去！
- I came to eat. - Get out!
尼什基！
Nishky!
给你
Here.
尼什基，我急需要找到多布里沃伊
Nishky, I need to find Dobrivoye. Right now.
警察检查站  弗拉涅  南塞尔维亚  南斯拉夫王国
Police checkpoint, Vranje, Southern Serbia, SCH Kingdom
醒醒！
Wake up!
- 怎么了? - 该干活了
- What now? - Time to work.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
那家伙一直在睡觉
That guy sleeps all the time.
等一下
Hold it.
- 去哪儿? - 贝尔格莱德
- Where to? - Belgrade.
- 巴塞尔·特纳瓦茨? - 没错
- Basyl Trnavatz? - That's right.
巴塞尔是你什么人？
Who's that, Basyl?
我的叔叔，阿姨还有其他人
My uncle, aunt and other family.
他们都死在同一天？
They all died on the same day?
不，不，我们把叔叔挖出来了
No no. We unburied the uncle.
下车
Get out of the car.
你听说比托拉肺结核爆发的事了吗？
Did you hear about the tuberculosis outbreak in Bitola?
每天都有人死去
People are dying every day.
- 你在耍我们吗? - 你要带他们去哪？
- Are you fucking with us? - And where are you taking them?
他们从贝尔格莱德来到比托拉，我要带他们回家
They came to Bitola from Belgrade. I'm taking them back home.
- 给他们一个体面的葬礼 - 打开！
- To give them a proper burial. - Open it up!
- 你不信吗? - 快打开，该死的！
- You don't trust me anymore? - Open up, goddammit!
让我来介绍一下我的叔叔
Let me introduce you to my uncle.
看他多帅啊
Look how handsome he was.
女人们都为他疯狂，多么英俊的小伙子啊
Women were mad about him. Such a good-looking' fella he was.
天啊! 盖上
Jesus! Close that thing...
- 你看，风流不减当年 - 你他妈快闭嘴吧！
- See, he still has it. - Get the fuck out of here!
- 现在，让我给你看看我的阿姨 - 我们看够了! 快滚！
- Now, let me show you my aunt. - We saw enough! Go away!
滚滚滚
Move on, dammit! Move that.
祝你们好运！
Cheers!
布鲁塞尔  比利时
BRUSSELS, BELGIUM
彼得 · 尼古拉耶维奇
Peter Nikolaevich.
索罗金，从贝尔格莱德来的
Sorokin arrived from Belgrade.
让他过来
Send him over.
怎么了，索罗金？
What is it, Sorokin?
我有个坏消息，将军
I have bad news, General sir.
说吧
Speak.
我们在贝尔格莱德的教堂..
Our church in Belgrade...
怎么了？
What about it?
被抢劫了
It has been robbed.
还有吗？
And...
它被偷走了
It has been stolen.
下午好
Good afternoon.
我刚才看到那个人虐待你
I saw that man mistreating you earlier.
对不起，我还没有自我介绍，我是斯坦科
Sorry, I haven't introduced myself, I'm Stanko.
我是个妓女，不用那么客气
And I'm a whore, no need to be polite if you wanna get some.
你是警察? 你要逮捕我？
You a copper? You gonna arrest me?
- 不不 - 那你想干嘛？
- No, no. - Then what?
- 我只是想确保... - 确保什么？
- I just wanted to make sure that... - That what?
你没事
That you're fine.
哦，那个
Oh, that.
你穿的是什么? 看起来很漂亮，是吧？
What's that you're wearing? Made yourself all pretty, huh?
嘿，小子，你需要什么？
Hey boy, what do you need?
我不找你
From you, nothing.
是这样吗? 那可不行
Is that so? That won't work.
你如果想骑她，给我钱，想骑多久就骑多久
You wanna fuck, give me the money and ride as long as you want.
- 你在看什么? - 我没有
- What're you looking' at? - I'm not.
- 滚到你的角落去! - 好的，我这就去！
- Fuck off to your corner! - Alright. I'm going!
- 你把我们当牲口一样对待 - 滚开，听到了吗？
- You're treatin' us like cattle. - Fuck off, do you hear me?
你们要是吹的跟你们吹的一样好，我现在就是个公爵了
If you fucked as good as you swore I'd be a duke by now.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
这是你的新女朋友吗? 多布里沃伊，你吓死我了
Is this your new girlfriend? Dammit Dobrivoye, you scared me.
你为什么吓唬妓女? 过来，有事找你
Why are you scarin' the whores? Come here, do something.
什么事
I'm listening.
把这个送到丘布拉
Take this over to Chubura.
- 斯坦科! 过来... - 让我..
- Stanko! Come over here... - Let me just...
听着，我每晚都在这个角落
Just listen. I'm here at this corner every night.
所以，来找我
So, drop by.
- 再见 - 好的
- Goodbye. - Yeah.
你这里还有前国王的画吗？
You still have a painting of the ex-king here?
欧布里诺维奇是我的王朝，那些卡拉迪约杰维奇是混蛋
The Obrenovich are my dynasty. Those Karadjordjevichs are dicks.
给我一盘豆子，再来一瓶酒！
Give us some beans and a bottle of wine!
我知道
I know.
把你的手放在口袋里，装作有枪的样子
Put your hand in your pocket as if you have a gun and frown.
亲爱的多布里沃伊，你去哪儿了？
Where've you been, my dear Dobrivoye?
你他妈是谁？
Who the hell are you?
你会告诉我巴塞尔·特纳瓦茨在哪里
I'm the one you'll tell where Trnavatz is.
我不认识你，也不认识特纳瓦茨
I don't know you and I don't know Trnavatz.
站起来，我们到外面去
Now, get up and get the fuck out of here.
你为什么这么生气，我亲爱的多布里沃伊？
Why are you so mad, my dear Dobrivoye?
例行警察检查! 你们接着吃
Routine police check! Keep up your work.
把他拖出来！
Pull him out. Pull him out!
怎么回事? 因为我们抢了俄罗斯人的生意，是吧？
What's the matter? Russians hate the competition, huh?
你搞错了
You got it wrong.
我为警察工作，你可以告诉我一切
I work for the police, you can tell me everything.
特纳瓦茨在哪儿？
Where's Trnavatz?
我没听见，他在哪儿，你这混蛋? ！
I didn't hear you. Where is he, you fucker?!
他嘴里含着枪，不能告诉你
He can't tell you with the gun in his mouth.
你是在审问他还是想杀了他？
Are you questioning him or trying to kill him?
我还没决定
I haven't decided yet.
谢谢，太好了
Thank you. Excellent.
去准备下一幕，你觉得怎么样？
Set the next scene. What are your impressions?
沃因？
Voyin?
我不喜欢芭蕾，但是看起来很有趣
Well I'm not into ballet, but it seems very interesting.
太好了，贝尔格莱德会永远感激你的
Marvellous. Belgrade will be eternally grateful to you.
我们也很感激
We are grateful too.
你会和玛雅一起去首映式吗？
Will you come to the premiere with Maya?
- 再说吧 - 玛雅夫人
- We'll see. - Mrs. Maya.
安吉丽娜，你做完了吗？
Angelina, you finished it?
太棒了，和我画的一模一样，麻烦你了
Wonderful. Exactly as I drew it.
一点也不麻烦，夫人
It was no bother at all, madam.
谢谢，还有...按照约定
Thank you, and... As agreed.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 再见 - 再见
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
沃因! 祝你好运! 再见！
Voyin! Good luck! Bye!
剧院是一个大妓院，看来确实如此
It's true that the theatre is one big brothel.
- 久基奇夫人 - 下午好
- Mrs. Djukich. - Good afternoon.
你的服装还没准备好
Your costume isn't ready yet.
扔掉
Throw it away.
给我做一件和她一模一样的衣服
Make me the exact same dress as hers.
但是夫人，那是原创的素描，她会知道的
But madam, that's an original sketch, she'll know that I'm...
一样的，明白吗？
The same one, please. Understood?
我希望在舞会之前完成
And I want it done before the ball.
拉吉丁..
Rakitin...
我丈夫只能和我一起去你的首映式
My husband can come to your premiere only with me.
再见
Goodbye.
谢谢，这是很重要的信息
Thank you. This is important information.
- 这个消息只有你知道 - 我会给你..
- Nobody else knows it. - I'll give your...
我会代你向索罗金上校问好
I'll give your regards to Colonel Sorokin.
谢廖莎，带上人，我们走
Seryozha, bring the men, we're leaving.
- 怎么了? - 警方有线索了
- Why, what happened? - The police have a lead.
你为什么要问我？
What's going on, why are you questioning me?
这里我说了算，服从命令！
I'm in charge here, follow the orders!
快走！
Move it!
阿廖沙
Alyosha.
多布里沃伊，你在吗？
Dobrivoye, are you there?
他到底去哪儿了？
Where the fuck has he gone?
所有事情都得我一个人做
Got to do everything by myself.
别盖上，特纳瓦茨，你可能需要它
Don't close it, Trnavatz. You may need it.
警察，我无能为力
The cops. There was nothing I could do.
- 收入不错吧? - 去你妈的
- Good harvest, huh? - Stick it up your arse.
现在，告诉我... 是谁替 Tatko 报了仇？
Now, tell me... Who avenged Tatko?
我们为什么要给他报仇？
Why would we do it?
我们很高兴俄国人杀了他
We were happy when the Russians killed him.
他是个人渣
He was a real scum.
是谁杀了那个俄国神父？
And who killed the Russian priest?
那我这么问吧，谁接替了Tatko的位置？
Let's try it like this. Who succeeded Tatko?
我不能告诉你
That I can't tell you.
我不能告诉你，因为我不知道！
That I can't tell you. Because I don't know!
从没见过那个人，没人见过
Never saw the man. Nobody did.
- 给他戴上手铐 - 探长
- Put him in handcuffs. - Inspector.
看来你的调查有进展了
I see you're making progress in the investigation.
恭喜你，长官，我通常会注意到我被跟踪了
Congratulations, captain. I usually notice when I'm followed.
这是你的商品，竞争对手已经决定离开了
Here's your merchandise. The competition has decided to leave.
谢谢你，督察
Thank you, inspector.
但我需要这两个人活着，我需要审问他们
But I need these two alive. I have to question them.
你很清楚这是不可能的，督察
You know very well that is not possible, inspector.
他们不需要因为误会而死
They don't need to die over a misunderstanding.
我见过很多人死去
I've seen many deaths.
其中很少有不是误会的
Very few of them made sense.
我们的神父在我们的教堂被杀
The murder of our priest, at our church...
可不是误会
was not a misunderstanding.
什么神父？
What priest?
我不会杀神父的，那会带来厄运的！
I'd never kill a clergyman, it's bad luck!
先生们这里有点小误会
Gentlemen, there's been a little misunderstanding.
- 我们是贝尔格莱德警察...-嘿，等等! 等等！
- We're Belgrade police... - Hey, hold on! Wait!
退后，你这个笨蛋! 他们很清楚我们是谁
Back off, you fool! They know very well who we are.
- 左边还是右边? - 什么？
- The right one or the left one? - What?
- 谁杀了神父? - 我不知道！
- Who killed the priest? - I don't know!
- 谁杀了神父? - 我真的不知道! 我发誓！
- Who killed the priest? - I don't know! I swear!
我们为什么要报复一个俄罗斯神父？
Why would we wanna get revenge on a Russian priest?
修道士禁止一切复仇行为
The Monk has forbidden any act of vengeance.
修道士是谁？
Who is the Monk?
我们的新老板，接替Tatko的人
Our new boss. He replaced Tatko.
好了，队长，你问过他们了
There, captain. You questioned them.
上尉，让我们杀了这些混蛋，以儆效尤
Captain, let's shoot these bastards, to set an example.
上尉! 你是维兰格尔将军光荣军队的军官
Captain! You're an officer of the general Vrangel's glorious army.
你知道不能杀平民
You know better than killing civilians.
好吧
Alright.
告诉你老板
Tell that Monk of yours...
他的生活变得非常痛苦
that his life has just got very complicated.
我们都没见过他
We don't even know him, man.
我们一定会认识他的
We'll make sure we get to know him.
而你..
And you...
找出杀害尼钦斯基的凶手
Find us Nizhinsky's killer.
快点
Quickly.
瓦西里耶，把车开走
Vasiliye, the truck
去给他缝针
Go get him stitched.
你不会把我们送进监狱吧？
You're not taking us to prison, huh?
该死的混蛋..
Fucking jerk...
- 是我 - 什么事这么急？
- It's me. - What's so urgent?
我们的卡车..
That truck of ours...
被俄国人截了
The Russians got it.
怎么回事？
What do you mean?
我不知道，有人出卖了我们
I don't know, boss. Someone ratted on us.
我会负全责的
I'm taking full responsibility.
把货找回来
Find them.
我会的
I will.
- 马上搞定 - 好的
- Get it done, now. - Okay.
- 到修道院来 - 明白
- And come to the monastery. - Understood.
多布里沃伊，老大，我肯定
It was Dobrivoye, boss. I'm sure of it.
没有其他人了
There's no one else.
塔纳西耶维奇先生，我们来这里干什么？
Mr. Tanasiyevich, what are we here for?
警察的目的是什么？
What's the purpose of police?
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
我知道什么不是
I certainly know what's not.
我的意思是，我知道我们不能总是照章办事..
I mean, I know we can't always play by the book...
等一下
Hold on a sec.
难道我们不是确定了Tatko的人与此事无关吗？
Haven't we found that Tatich's men are not involved?
如果我们相信他们的话
If we trust their word.
你真的认为那个神父是因为鸦片而死的吗？
Do you really think the priest had died because of opium?
- 可能不是 - 看到没? 我们得一步一步来
- Probably not. - See? We got to go step by step.
你知道吗，我要写一份报告给局长
You know what, I'll write a report to the commissioner.
我想看看他的反应
I want to see his response.
写报告
Write the report.
给自己找个新搭档吧，以后别跟我一起工作了
And find yourself a new partner. I won't work with you anymore.
看啊! 你真的来了
Look at that! You really came.
是你让我来的
Well, you told me to.
是的
I did.
你这么干净，我可以免费跟你做
When I see you all tidy like that, I'd give it to you for free.
但是不行
But I can't.
你们有没有... 房间什么的？
And do you have... A room or something?
那要看情况，你有钱吗？
Depends. Do you have the money?
- 有 - 开个玩笑
- Yes. - Just kidding.
跟我来
Come over here.
把那件德国西装脱了，别弄皱了
Take off that German suit, don't wanna wrinkle it.
你有孩子？
You have a kid?
你是来聊天的还是来做爱的？
Did you come here to have a chat or to have a shag?
脱掉你的衣服
Take off your clothes.
玛雅！
Maya!
玛雅夫人！
Madam Maya!
康斯坦丁，把帽子戴上
Constantine, put your hat back on.
玛雅，你的服装很完美
Maya, your costume is perfect.
我不知道它是否完美，我只想让它独一无二
I don't know if it's perfect, but I tried to make it unique.
不要生气
Don't get mad.
她终于从我这里偷走了一样东西
She finally stole something from me.
哎呀! 我们可什么都没听到
Oops! We didn't hear this.
久基奇先生! 久基奇夫人！
Mister Djukich! Mrs Djukich!
- 克丽丝塔! 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Krista, Krista! Good evening. - Good evening.
玛雅，很有创意
Maya, very original.
既然你决定偷我的戏服
Since you decided to steal my costume,
那你应该知道穿它应该不穿内裤的
you should've known that it should be worn without knickers.
帮我们登记吧
Let us register
你去哪儿了？
Where have you been?
- 玛雅，玛雅，你把底片... - 请走开
- Maya, Maya, did you bring them... - Go away, please.
如果你带来的话就告诉我，这很重要
Just tell me if you have them, it's important...
走开！
Go away!
滚开，娘炮，否则我就把它塞进你的屁股里
Back off, pansy, or I'll stick it up your arse.
我知道你肯定会喜欢的！
And I know for sure you'd like it!
我只需要问她一件事，玛雅你有没有..
Just need to ask her. Maya did you...
- 玛雅，你会后悔的 - 快滚
- Maya, you'll regret this. - Fuck off.
奈斯托维奇先生
Mr. Nestorovich...
你是个艺术家，美丽是你的专长
You're an artist. Beauty is your thing.
你认为今晚谁会赢？
Who do you think will win tonight?
久基奇夫人，毫无疑问
Madam Djukich, without any doubt.
你真会撒谎
You're a good liar, Avram.
请这位女士跳支舞
Ask the lady for a dance.
你想跳舞吗？
Would you like to dance?
你知道我对艺术家情有独钟..
Avram, you know I have a soft spot for artists...
你能和克丽丝塔跳支舞吗？
Would you please dance with Krista?
我们已经清点了大家的投票
We've counted your votes
现在让我来宣布最佳服装
and we will now pronounce the best costume.
开灯！
Lights!
获胜者是..
And the winner is...